purplecarrot.com 2019-06-29

# Privacy Policy | Purple Carrot

This website, [www.purplecarrot.com](https://www.purplecarrot.com/) (the “Website” or “Site”) provides plant-based meal delivery services (the “Services”). This Privacy Policy covers how The Purple Carrot ("Purple Carrot", “we”) collects, uses and shares Personally Identifiable Information (“PII” or “Personal Information”) we collect on the Site. PII includes information about you that is personally identifying such as your name, email address, home address, and phone number and which is not otherwise publicly available. PII may include other types of information depending on the legal definition of PII that applies in your physical location. Only the definition of PII that applies in your location will apply to you under this Privacy Policy.

Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms of Use, accessible at [www.purplecarrot.com/terms](http://www.purplecarrot.com/terms). This website is owned and operated by Three Limes, Inc. d/b/a The Purple Carrot.

## Agreement

By using this Site or Services, you accept and hereby expressly consent to our collection, use, and disclosure of your PII in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically to check the most recent modification date to ensure that you are aware of any changes in our processing of your PII. Your continued use of the Site or Services after any changes signifies your express consent to any such changes. If you do not agree to such changes, you must immediately stop using the Site. This Privacy Policy was last modified on June 15, 2017.

## Information Collection and Use; Choice and Consent

Sign Up

If you sign up for the Site through Facebook, we collect your email address and Facebook password. We may also collect information about you from Facebook, including PII, in accordance with the Facebook privacy policy and terms of use. If you sign up directly on the Site, we collect your first and last name, address, zip code, state, city and phone number.

We use this information to process your registration, identify you, activate and manage your account, create your user profile, respond to your requests and inquiries and provide you with requested Services. We also use this information to communicate with you about your deliveries and account and to send you promotional information about Purple Carrot.

Recipes

When you request a recipe, we collect your email address in order to provide the recipe and to send you promotional emails.

When You Contact Us

When you contact us through our Contact Us form, we collect your name and email address in order to respond to you and to send you promotional emails.

Purchases

When you make a purchase on the Site, such as a subscription or Gift Card, your payment card information, order number and email address is collected by our third party payment processor in order to process your transaction. The information collected includes your payment card number, CVV and expiration month, in addition to billing information such as your name and billing address. If you purchase a subscription, our third party payment processor retains your information in order to process your regular subscription payments.

Gift Cards

If you purchase a Gift Card, we collect your name and email address and the name and email of the person receiving the Gift Card in order to provide the Gift Card. In order to redeem a Gift Card, the gift recipient must Sign Up for an account on the Site and provide the requested Personal Information.

Refer a Friend

We use a third party service provider, such as Friend Buy, to operate our Refer a Friend feature. If you refer a friend to the Site, the information you provide will be collected by Friend Buy in accordance with the terms of their privacy policy. Friend Buy provides us with a copy of the information collected by them about you. We use this information to ensure the referral credits are given in accordance with the current offering. We also collect your friend’s email address in order to contact your friend and provide the referral credit We will also use your friend’s email address to send promotional emails about Purple Carrot.

Postings

The Site allows users to post comments in public areas of the Site and on social media sites, such as Facebook. If you wish to post a comment, your name and any other information you post will appear with your comment on areas of the Site and/or on social media sites that can be viewed by others. We may collect the information you post. Please be aware that any information you post on public areas of the Site may be copied, used and disclosed by others. Public postings are not covered by the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Jobs

If you apply for a job with Purple Carrot, we will collect your first and last name, email, phone number, address, photo, resume, and cover letter, which may include other information about you, including PII. You may also apply for a job with us using your LinkedIn profile. We will collect the information you provide to us. We will also collect information about you from LinkedIn if you provide your LinkedIn profile, in accordance with LinkedIn’s policies. We use this information to assess your qualifications for open positions and to contact you if we deem necessary.

Email Addresses and Promotional Messages

We collect email addresses of users and their friends that are provided to us through the Site or Services. We use these emails to send promotional messages about Purple Carrot. You may opt out of receiving these emails by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send or by contacting us.

Information Choices

It is always your choice whether or not to provide us with such information. If you do provide PII to the Site, you are giving your express consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your PII as described in this Privacy Policy. If you choose not to provide the requested information you may not be able to access certain features or functions of this Site and you will not have access to the Services. You may access, change or delete your information at any time as described below. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send or by contacting us.

## Retention of Your Information

We will retain your information, including Personal Information, as long as you maintain an account with us or as needed to provide the Services. We will retain your information, including Personal Information, after your account is closed if we believe it is necessary to do so, such as for legal compliance purposes, to resolve disputes, enforce our agreements or otherwise operate our business.

## Cookies

When you visit the Site, we use session “cookies,” a piece of information stored on your computer temporarily and deleted from the user’s device when the browser is closed, to allow us to uniquely identify your browser while you are browsing or interacting with the Site.  Session cookies also help us confirm your identity and are required in order to log into your account. We also use cookies to help us improve the Site.  If you wish to prevent cookies from being used as you navigate our Site, you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies and/or indicate when a cookie is being sent.

Users who disable their web browsers’ ability to accept cookies will be able to browse the Site, but will not be able to access or take advantage of all of the features and Services on the Site. We therefore recommend you do not block or disable these cookies. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been sent and how to manage, as well as delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "opens new window").

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

We disclose Personal Information that we collect to third parties who provide services that you request. We disclose PII to third party vendors who help us operate the Site, such as our credit card payment processors and delivery services. These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform specific tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use your information for any other purpose.

We will disclose your information in response to valid legal process, for example, in response to a court order, a subpoena or other legal request for information, and/or to comply with applicable legal and regulatory reporting requirements. We also may disclose your information in response to a law enforcement agency's request or other request for information from the U.S. or other government entities, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our products and/or services and with applicable laws, or as otherwise required or permitted by law or consistent with legal requirements. In addition, we may transfer your information to an entity or individual that acquires, buys, or Purple Carrots with us, or our other business units.

## Log Data

We collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Service ("Log Data"). This Log Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics.

In addition, we use third party services such as Google Analytics that collect, monitor and analyze this type of information in order to increase our Service's functionality. These third party service providers have their own privacy policies addressing how they use such information.

We also use advanced analytics service providers like Mouseflow that provide session replay, heatmaps, funnels, form analytics, feedback campaigns, and similar features/functionality, so that we can learn and enhance your site experience. We do not use them to track personally identifiable information, collect information on sites visited outside of our domain, or any activity outside of your browser. If you'd like to opt-out, you can do so at <https://mouseflow.com/opt-out>.

## Security

The security of your Personal Information is important to us, and we strive to implement and maintain reasonable, commercially acceptable security procedures and practices appropriate to the nature of the information we store, in order to protect it from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure. However, please be aware that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and we are unable to guarantee the absolute security of the Personal Information we have collected from you.

## Social Media Sites and Widgets

The Site includes Social Media Features from social media sites such as the Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest and Instagram that run on our site. Please note that our Site is not sponsored or endorsed by Facebook or any other social media website, which are trademarked and owned by third parties and not by us. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. We will collect any information you give us permission to access from social media websites via social media authorization tokens (for example, Facebook).

## Your California Privacy Rights; California Do Not Track Disclosures 

We support Do Not Track ("DNT"). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked. You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

If you are a resident of the State of California, under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84, you have the right to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of personal information that we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for direct marketing purposes. You may request this information by email at [hello@purplecarrot.com](mailto:hello@purplecarrot.com)

## International Users; Transfer of Information to the U.S.

Our Site and Services are provided and hosted in the United States. If you access our Site or use our Services from outside the United States, your Personal Information will be transferred and processed in the United States in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Please note that the U.S. has not been recognized as providing an adequate level of protection according to EU data protection requirements, but we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that Personal Information is treated securely as described in this Privacy. By accessing the Site, using our Services or providing Personal Information, you expressly and unambiguously consent to such transfer, processing, storage and disclosure in the U.S.

## Links to Other Sites; Transactions with Third Parties

The Site may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies and statements of other sites to understand their information practices. Our Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by our Site and Services.

The Purple Carrot is not responsible for and will not be a party to any transactions between you and a third party provider of products, information or services. Purple Carrot does not monitor such transactions or ensure the confidentiality of your PII, including credit card information, for any third party transaction. Any separate charges or obligations you incur in your dealings with these third parties linked to Purple Carrot's Site are solely your responsibility.

## Children’s Privacy

Our Site is directed to individuals who are the age of majority or older in their jurisdiction. We do not knowingly collect information from children. If you believe your child has provided information to the Site please contact us using the information provided below.

## Accessing Your Information

You may access, review or change your PII by logging into your account. For information on cancelling your account, please see our Terms of Use at [www.purplecarrot.com/terms](https://www.purplecarrot.com/terms).

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us.

## Terms of Use 

Please also visit our Terms of Use section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our Site and Services at [www.purplecarrot.com/terms](https://www.purplecarrot.com/terms).
